Nevada Arts Council "Honest Horses" exhibition collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Nevada Arts Council "Honest Horses" exhibition collection 1999-2003
AFC 2014/019
Morin, Paula, 1945-
Nevada Arts Council
sound recordings: 126 sound cassettes: analog.
sound recordings: 3 microcassettes: analog.
manuscripts: 5 boxes: 25 linear inches
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of field recordings of interviews and administrative files generated by and curated by Paula Morin and the Nevada Arts Council for an exhibition titled "Honest Horses: a portrait of the mustang in the Great Basin," circa 2002, and later as a traveling exhibition. Morin photographed wild horses in the Great Basin and interviewed Nevada residents and others about the complex issues regarding wild horses and ecology. Interviewees include ranchers, buckaroos, outfitters, horse trainers, veterinarians, professors of animal science, researchers from the United States Department of Agriculture, the Bureau of Land Management, the Nevada Department of Conservation and Natural Resources, the Nature Conservancy, the Commission for Preservation of Wild Horses, the National Wild Horse and Burro Center, National Mustang Association, other advocacy organizations, and writers. Most interviewees were from Nevada, others were from California, Idaho, New Mexico, Oklahoma, and Oregon. Manuscripts include the edited narratives of the interviewees; edited copies of transcripts; biographical profiles; transcripts from speeches; copies of published articles on feral horses and habitat; pamphlets; and correspondence with Paula Morin and with folklorist Andrea Graham of the Nevada Arts Council. Selected narratives were included in Paula Morin's book titled Honest Horses: Wild Horses in the Great Basin (Reno: University of Nevada Press, c2006).
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Abbey, Bob; Budiansky, Stephen; Flores, Dan L. (Dan Louie), 1948-; Graham, Andrea; Grandin, Temple; Liu, Irwin K. M.; Mathis, Dave; Mattise, Samuel N.; Mitchell, Waddie, 1950-; Morin, Paula, 1945-; Nachlinger, Janet L. (Janet Lynn); Shrake, Richard; Vavra, Martin
Organizations
Nevada Arts Council
Subjects
Animal scientists--West (U.S.)--Interviews.; Conservation biology--Great Basin.; Ecologists--Great Basin--Interviews.; Horse trainers--Nevada--Interviews.; Land use--Nevada.; Ranchers--Nevada--Interviews.; Veterinarians--Interviews.; Wild horses--Great Basin.; Wild horses--Nevada.
Places
Great Basin.
Form/Genre
Articles.; Correspondence.; Interviews (Sound recordings); Manuscripts.; Oral histories.; Transcripts.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series, Administrative and Interview Documentation, which is organized alphabetically by interviewee's last name.
Acquisition
Nevada Arts Council; 2014.
Custodial History
The collection was initially deposited at the Nevada Arts Council in 2001; in 2014 it was acquired by the American Folklife Center.
Related Material
See related photographs in the Paula Morin collection: Honest horses, wild horses in the Great Basin (AFC 2013/038).
http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/eadafc.af014003
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access to recordings may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Bibliography
Selected interviews published in: Morin, Paula. Honest horses: wild horses in the Great Basin (Reno: University of Nevada Press, c2006)
History Note
The Nevada Arts Council and Paula Morin collaborated, 1999-2001, to collect a series of administrative files, interviews, field recordings, and photographs which documented the horses of the Great Basin. These materials were used to create an exhibit titled "Honest Horses: A Portrait of the Mustang in Nevada's Great Basin," which later became a traveling exhibit.
Scope and Content
Collection of field recordings of interviews and administrative files generated by and curated by Paula Morin and the Nevada Arts Council for an exhibition titled "Honest Horses: a portrait of the mustang in the Great Basin," circa 2002, and later as a traveling exhibition. Morin photographed wild horses in the Great Basin and interviewed Nevada residents and others about the complex issues regarding wild horses and ecology. Interviewees include ranchers, buckaroos, outfitters, horse trainers, veterinarians, professors of animal science, researchers from the United States Department of Agriculture, the Bureau of Land Management, the Nevada Department of Conservation and Natural Resources, the Nature Conservancy, the Commission for Preservation of Wild Horses, the National Wild Horse and Burro Center, National Mustang Association, other advocacy organizations, and writers. Most interviewees were from Nevada, others were from California, Idaho, New Mexico, Oklahoma, and Oregon. Manuscripts include the edited narratives of the interviewees; edited copies of transcripts; biographical profiles; transcripts from speeches; copies of published articles on feral horses and habitat; pamphlets; and correspondence with Paula Morin and with folklorist Andrea Graham of the Nevada Arts Council. Selected narratives were included in Paula Morin's book titled Honest Horses: Wild Horses in the Great Basin (Reno: University of Nevada Press, c2006).
Container List
- Series 1: Administrative
  - Finding Aid (Box 1)
- Series II: Interviews
  - The Interviews were conducted by Paula Morin, 1999-2002
  - Abbey, Bob, 2000-08-19, Transcript of interview with Bob Abbey, Bureau of Land Management state director, Reno, Nevada. (Box-folder 1/1)
  - AFC 2014/019: SR001, 1 audio cassette
  - Anderson, Glade, 2002-09-16, Transcript of interview with Glade Anderson, Bureau of Land Management supervisory wild horse and burro specialist, Sparks, Nevada. (Box-folder 1/2)
  - AFC 2014/019: SR002, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR003, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Andrae, Jim, 2000-04-12, Transcript of interview with Jim Andrae ranch manager, Nevada. (Box-folder 1/3)
  - AFC 2014/019: SR004, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR005, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Arigoni, Leland, 2002-03-26 (Box-folder 1/4)
    Leland Arigoni is a buckaroo. A personal narrative included. No transcript available.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR006, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR007, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Artz, Jack, 2000-05-19 (Box-folder 1/5)
    Transcript of interview with Jack Artz, range scientist, Cool, California.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR008, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR009, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Ashley, Mike, 1999-12-10 (Box-folder 1/6)
    Transcript of interview with Mike Ashley, geneticist, United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) Agricultural Research Service.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR010, 1 audio cassette
  - Barcomb, Cathy, Undated (Box-folder 1/7)
    One proposal included. No transcript available.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR011, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR012, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Blunk, Katie, 2002-04-09 (Box-folder 1/8)
    Transcript of interview with Katie Blunk, field veterinarian, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR013, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR014, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Brown, Bob, 2000-05-09 (Box-folder 1/9)
    Transcript of interview with Bob Brown, Bureau of Land Management wild horse and burro specialist, Ely, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR015, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR016, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Brown, Joyce, 2002-04-17 (Box-folder 1/10)
    Transcript of interview with Joyce Brown, real estate agent, Las Vegas, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR017, 1 audio cassette
  - Budiansky, Stephen, 2002-10-22 (Box-folder 1/11)
    Transcript of interview with Stephen Budiansky, correspondent for the The Atlantic Monthly, Leesburg, Virginia.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR018, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR019, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Burkhardt, Wayne, 2000-7-12, and 2001-10-30 (Box-folder 1/12)
    Transcript of two interviews with Wayne Burkhardt, range scientist, Indian Valley, Idaho.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR020, 1 audio cassette
  - AFC 2014/019: SR021, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR022, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Cassas, Frank, 2002-05-14 (Box-folder 1/13)
    Transcript of interview with Frank Cassas, attorney, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR023, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR024, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Cattoor, Dave, 1999-08-25 (Box-folder 1/14)
    Transcript of interview with Dave Cattoor, Bureau of Land Management contract mustanger, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR025, 1 of 2 mini audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR026, 2 of 2 mini audio cassettes
  - Cirelli, Al, 2000-08-18 (Box-folder 1/15)
    Transcript of interview with Al Cirelli, horse specialist, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR027, 1 of 3 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR028, 2 of 3 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR029, 3 of 3 audio cassettes
  - Cleary, Rex, 1999-12-09 (Box-folder 2/16)
    Transcript of interview with Rex Cleary, senior resource specialist, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR030, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR031, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Clements, Charlie, 2002-02-08 (Box-folder 2/17)
    Transcript of interview with Charlie Clements, rangeland scientist, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR032, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR033, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Davies, Stacy, 2002-08-20 (Box-folder 2/18)
    Transcript of interview with Stacy Davies, ranch manager at Roaring Springs Ranch, Oregon.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR034, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR035, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Davis, Steve, 2002-11-18 (Box-folder 2/19)
    Transcript of interview with Steve Davis, professor of animal science at Oregon State University, Corvallis, Oregon.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR036, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR037, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Depaoli, Ed, 1999-11-19 (Box-folder 2/20)
    Transcript of interview with Ed Depaoli, rancher, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR038, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR039, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Dohnel, Dave, 2002-10-17 (Box-folder 2/21)
    Transcript of interview with Dave Dohnel, wild horse outfitter, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR040, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR041, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Falen, John, 2000-08-22 (Box-folder 2/22)
    Transcript of interview with John Falen, rancher, Orovada, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR042, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR043, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Fisher, Charlie, 2002-01-16 (Box-folder 2/23)
    Charlie Fisher is a range conservationist with the Bureau of Indian Affairs. No transcript available.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR044, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR045, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Flores, Dan, 2003-01-10 (Box-folder 2/24)
    Transcript of interview with Dan Flores, professor of history at the University of Montana. Interview conducted in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR046, 1 audio cassette
  - Frazier, Gordon, Undated (Box-folder 2/25)
    No transcript available.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR047, 1 audio cassette
  - Gianola, Jim, 2000-01-04 (Box-folder 2/26)
    Transcript of interview with Jim Gianola, Bureau of Land Management wild horse specialist, Carson City, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR048, 1 audio cassette
  - Grandin, Temple, Undated (Box-folder 2/27)
    Temple Grandin is a professor of animal science at Colorado State University. No transcript available.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR049, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR050, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Hall, Ron, 2002-08-14 (Box-folder 2/28)
    Transcript of interview with Ron Hall, Bureau of Land Management wild horse specialist, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR051, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR052, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Harding, Ron, 2002-03-06 (Box-folder 2/29)
    Transcript of interview with Ron Harding, range conservationist, Burns, Oregon.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR053, 1 of 3 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR054, 2 of 3 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR055, 3 of 3 audio cassettes
  - Hartgrove, Tom, 2002-04-17 (Box-folder 2/30)
    Transcript of interview with Tom Hartgrove, veterinarian, Las Vegas, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR056, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR057, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Heaverne, Cliff, 2000-05-11 (Box-folder 3/31)
    Transcript of interview with Cliff Heaverne, pilot and owner of High Desert Helicopters, Fallon, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR058, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR059, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Johnson, Larry, 2001-08-10 (Box-folder 3/32)
    Transcript of interview with Larry Johnson, president of Black Eagle Consulting, Inc., Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR060, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR061, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Kent, Ira, 2000-02-07 (Box-folder 3/33)
    Transcript of interview with Ira Kent, rancher, Fallon, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR062, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR063, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Kipping, Sharon, Undated (Box-folder 3/34)
    Transcript of interview with Sharon Kipping, manager of the Bureau of Land Management National Wild Horse and Burro Center at Palomino Valley, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR064, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR065, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Kirk, Mike, 2000-03-07 (Box-folder 3/35)
    Transcript of interview with Mike Kirk, veterinarian, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR066, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR067, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Lamb, Sheldon and Lamb, Isabel, 1999-10-24 (Box-folder 3/36)
    Interview with Sheldon and Isabel Lamb, ranchers, Fallon, Nevada. No sound recording.
  - Lappin, Dawn, 1999-10-27 and 2001-09-07 (Box-folder 3/37)
    Transcript of two interviews with Dawn Lappin, director of Wild Horse Organized Assistance, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR068, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR069, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR070, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR071, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Liu, Irwin, 2002-05-02 (Box-folder 3/38)
    Transcript of interview with Liu Irwin, professor at University of California Davis, Davis, California.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR072, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR073, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Martin, Sunny, 2000-05-08 (Box-folder 3/39)
    Transcript of interview with Sunny Martin, founder of the American Bashkir Curly Registry, Ely, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR074, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR075, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Marvel, Tom, 2001-08-20 (Box-folder 3/40)
    Transcript of interview with Tom Marvel, rancher, Elko, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR076, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR077, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Mathis, Dave, 2001-10-03 (Box-folder 3/41)
    Transcript of interview with Dave Mathis, writer, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR078, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR079, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Mattise, Sam, 2002-04-09 (Box-folder 3/42)
    Transcript of interview with Sam Mattise, Bureau of Land Management wild horse specialist, Boise, Idaho.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR080, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR081, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - McFadden, Gary, 2000-02-04 (Box-folder 3/43)
    Transcript of interview with Gary McFadden, Bureau of Land Management wild horse specialist, Las Vegas, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR082, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR083, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Miller, Rick, Undated (Box-folder 3/44)
  - AFC 2014/019: SR084, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR085, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Mitchell, Waddie, 2002-01-30 (Box-folder 3/45)
    Transcript of interview with Mitchell Waddie, rancher, Elko, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR086, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR087, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Molini, William, 2001-11-14 (Box-folder 4/46)
    Transcript of interview with William Molini, former director of the Nevada Department of Fish and Game, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR088, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR089, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Morris, Bob, 2002-10-28 (Box-folder 4/47)
    Transcript of interview with Bob Morris, president and chief executive officer of Stormont Laboratories, Inc., Woodland, California.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR090, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR091, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Nachlinger, Jan and Provencher, Louis, 2002-10-07 (Box-folder 4/48)
    Transcript of interview with Jan Nachlinger and Louis Provencher, botanist/plant ecologist and range ecologist, The Nature Conservancy, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR092, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR093, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Nappe, Tina, 2002-09-12 (Box-folder 4/49)
    Transcript of interview with Tina Nappe, former director of Nevadaworks, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR094, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR095, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Neubert, Bryan, 2000-01-26 (Box-folder 4/50)
    Transcript of interview with Bryan Neubert, horse clinician, Alturas, California.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR096, 1 audio cassette
  - Nunn, Gene, 2000-12-29 (Box-folder 4/51)
    Transcript of interview with Gene Nunn, Bureau of Land Management horse wrangler, Susanville, California.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR097, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR098, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Pellegrini, Steve, 2000-11-14 (Box-folder 4/52)
    Transcript of interview with Steve Pellegrini, biology teacher at Yerington High School, Yerington, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR099, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR100, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Pogacnik, Thomas, 2000-06-29 (Box-folder 4/53)
    Transcript of interview with Thomas Pogacnik, Bureau of Land Management senior supervisory wild horse specialist, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR101, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR102, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Pomi, Don, 2001-08-28 (Box-folder 4/54)
    Transcript of interview with Don Pomi, Bureau of Land Management horse wrangler, Fallon, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR103, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR104, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Portwood, Bruce, 1999-09-27 (Box-folder 4/55)
    Transcript of interview with Bruce Portwood, Bureau of Land Management wild horse specialist, Elko, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR105, 1 mini audio cassette
  - Price, B. Bryan, 2002-11-14 (Box-folder 4/56)
    Transcript of interview with B. Bryan Price, director of the Charles M. Russell Center for the Study of Art of the American West, Norman, Oklahoma.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR106, 1 audio cassette
  - Provencher, Louis (Box-folder 4/57)
    Transcript of interview with Louis Provencher and Jan Nachlinger, see box 4, folder 48. No sound recording.
  - Satterthwaite, Deloyd, 2000-05-27 (Box-folder 4/58)
    Transcript of interview with Deloyd Satterthwaite, rancher, Tuscaroroa, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR107, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR108, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Schulze, Vern, 2002-01-22 (Box-folder 4/59)
    Transcript of interview with Vern Schulze, Bureau of Land Management supervisory natural resources specialist, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR109, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR110, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Sewing, Richard, 2001-07-30 (Box-folder 5/60)
    Transcript of interview with Richard Sewing, director of the National Mustang Association, Ely, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR111, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR112, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Sharp, John, 2001-02-02 (Box-folder 5/61)
    Transcript of interview with John Sharp, horseman, Prineville, Oregon.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR113, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR114, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Shrake, Richard, Undated (Box-folder 5/62)
    Richard Shrake is a horseman. No transcript available.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR115, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR116, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Smith, Lloyd, 2000-02-04 (Box-folder 5/63)
    Transcript of interview with Lloyd Smith, former president of the National Wild Horse Association, Red Rock, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR117, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR118, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Tattam, Dave, 2000-02-03 (Box-folder 5/64)
    Transcript of interview with Dave Tattam, field director, Wild Horse Association, Las Vegas, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR119, 1 audio cassette
  - Turnipseed, Mike, 2001-09-11 (Box-folder 5/65)
    Transcript of interview with Mike Turnipseed, director of the Department of Conservation and Natural Resources, Carson City, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR120, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR121, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Uhalde, Gracian, 2002-08-09 (Box-folder 5/66)
    Transcript of interview with Gracian Uhalde, rancher, Ely, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR122, 1 audio cassette
  - Vavra, Marty, 2002-10-15 (Box-folder 5/67)
    Transcript of interview with Marty Vavra, professor of Rangeland Resources at Oregon State University, Burns, Oregon.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR123, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR124, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Winnepenninkx, John, 2001-12-08 (Box-folder 5/68)
    Transcript of interview with John Winnepenninkx, Bureau of Land Management wild horse specialist, Battle Mountain, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR125, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR126, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - Young, Jim, 1999-12-10, and 2002-01-29 (Box-folder 5/69)
    Transcript of two interviews with Jim Young, range historian, United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Agricultural Research Service, Reno, Nevada.
  - AFC 2014/019: SR127, 1 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR128, 2 of 2 audio cassettes
  - AFC 2014/019: SR129, 1 audio cassette